OFFICE OF INSTITUTIONAL RESEARCH RECORDS (UA030) 1970-1995
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
Office of Institutional Research Records1970-1995
nam_ua030
Contains studies and reports on the State University of New York at Albany based on research conducted by the Office of Institutional Research between 1970 and 1984.
Office of Institutional Research
1.0
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
Web Archives
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Biographical History
The Office of Institutional Research is a major source of official data and statistics about the University. The Office also has been a key developer of campus enrollment and revenue projections, especially concentrating on undergraduate admissions and financial aid databases. The Office also conducts special studies and databased analyses which measure organizational effectiveness and which support campus management.
Topics include the enrollment patterns of transfer students, geographic origins of students, trends in tuition and other basic student charges, instructional locations away from the main campus, and utilization of residence hall facilities.
Scope and Content Information
Includes analyses of faculty workloads, 1957-1969; memoranda, 1968-1978; profiles of student survey questionnaires, 1972-1978; annual reports, 1973-1975; academic library statistics, 1976-1984; statistical studies of trends in tuition and other student charges; and enrollment goals and projections.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection has no series, arranged alphabetically.
Subject and Genre Headings
State University of New York at Albany. Office of Institutional Research.; State University of New York at Albany -- Tuition.; Education, Higher -- Research -- New York (State) -- Albany.; Transfer students -- New York (State) -- Albany.; College facilities -- New York (State) -- Albany.; Web Archives
Container List
- Web Archives, 2000 April 8-2016 September 20; 1; 921
  Web crawling is managed through the Internet Archive's Archive-It service. This page includes links to both the university's collection and the Internet Archive's public collection.
  Surface-level crawling of www.albany.edu is performed daily which should includes most top-level webpages. Separate targeted crawls of every albany.edu subdomain are performed monthly to attempt to gather all content. This includes: www.albany.edu, www.rna.albany.edu, www.ctg.albany.edu, www.ualbanysports.com, www.albany.edu/rockefeller, www.albany.edu/cela, www.albany.edu/asrc, m.albany.edu, library.albany.edu, events.albany.edu, cstar.cestm.albany.edu, csda.albany.edu, and alumni.albany.edu
  Web Archives
  - http://www.albany.edu/ir/ - University Archives collection, 2013 May 8-2016 September 20 (Web-archive 1)
  - WARC file for http://www.albany.edu/ir/, (please see https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_ARChive for more details), 2013 May 8-2016 September 20 (Warc 1)
    WARC files are very large and difficult to work with. Your request may take time to process, and we may be unable to deliver your request remotely. Please consult an archivist if you are interested in researching with web archives.
  - http://www.albany.edu/ir/ - Internet Archive collection, 2000 April 8-2016 September 20 (Web-archive 2)
- Administrative Records, 1976-1992; 2; 1.0
  - Academic Library Statistics, 1976; 1978; 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Age Group & Sex of Students, 1975-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Application & Enrollment Patterns of Transfer Students, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Application & Enrollment Patterns of Transfer Students, 1976-1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Geographic Orgins of Students, vol. 1-3, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - High School Status of First Time Credit Course Students Report, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Instructional Locations away from the Main Campus, 1977-1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Inventory of Selected Interinstitutional Cooperative Arrangments as of January 1971 Report #19 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Non Credit Instructional Activities with Trend Information, 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Trends in Enrollment & Degrees Granted, 1983-1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Trends in Tuition & Other Basic Student Charges with Typical Student Costs, 1963-1995 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Utilization of Residence Hall Facilities, 1974-1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)